

INFO



Name Siva Kumar Mopuri.



F.No: G2, Sai Dhiran Residency KNR colony, Hyderabad, India.



Phone **+91 7416328974**

Email

Address



jobs.mopuri@gmail.com

Summary

Highly-Skilled software development professional bringing more than 9+ years in software design, development and integration using .NET Core with Microsoft Azure and Framework. Experienced technical lead specialized in front and back end development and well versed in all the stages of web application development cycle using Agile methodologies.

Knowledge on Azure web App, Azure VM, Azure Kubernetes , API Management , Azure AD , storage account and CosmosDB

Certifications



Exam AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals



Exam AZ-204: Microsoft Azure Developing solutions.

SIVA KUMAR MOPURI

Azure Integration Developer



WORK EXPERIENCE

December 2016 - Present

TATA Consultancy Services, Customer: Humana, USA.
Role: Azure Developer Associate, Project: Enterprise Messaging Applications.

Work Location: Hyderabad, India (Sep 2016 - Present)

- Azure(Cloud experience), Microservices, Asp.Net Core, Kubernetes, Web.Api, Asp.Net MVC, LINQ, SSRS & SSIS, WPF, MVVM, MOQ, WCF, JavaScript, jQuery.
- Azure Integration Services API Management, Azure functions, Service Bus, Azure Active Directory(AD), Oauth 2.0 authentication, Azure-VM.
- Worked closely with business stakeholders, software architects, production teams and across functional units to identify business needs and discuss solution options.
- Mentor, Provided Technical guidance and supported developers located in Onshore, Near-shore and Off-shore to assist in completing tasks.
- Setup Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment and educate developers to make use of CI/CD pipelines for all new developments.
- Designed and developed Enterprise level applications which process millions of requests per day.
- Enhanced Performance of processes handling millions of transactions per day by 10-20 times through redesigning SQL Tables and stored procedures.
- Responsible for code review and providing low level technical designs for the development Team.
- Helped the Team in migrating more than forty applications from TFS to Azure DevOps.
- Created a distributed plug and play architecture using REST API and ASP.NET MVC.
- Improved maintainability and scalability of the system by refactoring large pieces of code using Object Oriented Programming.



EDUCATION

2008 - 2011

JNTU Hyderabad, India

Master of Computers Applications

The degree focuses on the branch of engineering that pertains to the use of computers to collect, store, and share and protect information



SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

- Cloud Technology: Microsoft Azure
- Language: C# .NET, PL/SQL.
- Web Technologies: JQuery, Javascript, HTML, XML, JSON, CSS, Bootstrap.
- .NET Technologies: .NET Core 3.0, .NET Framework 4.8/4.7/4.6/4.5/4.0/3.0, Web Forms, Win Forms, Web Services, Azure DevOps, ASP.NET MVC 5.0/MVC 4.0/MVC 3.0, Web API, ADO.NET, WCF, LINQ, AJAX, WPF, Entity Framework 6.0/5.0/4.3.1/4.1, REST, SOAP, Service Virtualization, API Connect.
- Database: SQL Server 2016/2014/2012/2008/2005.
- Designing Tools: Visual Studio .NET (2019/2017/2015/2012/2010).
- Version Controller: Git/VSTS, TFS, SVN, CI/CD Pipeline using Azure DevOps.
- Reporting Services: SSRS, Crystal Reports.
- IDE: Postman, Fiddler, SOAP UI, Secure FX, Beyond Compare, XML Editor, Ultra Edit, Notepad++.
- Code Scan: IT Security Vault, SonarQube, checkmarx



Awards





Special Achievement



On the spot awards for the TCS in house

SOCIAL



https://www.linkedin.com

INTERESTS





SIVA KUMAR MOPURI

Azure Developer Associate



WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

2015 November – 2016 December

TATA Consultancy Services, Customer: Humana, USA.

Work Location: Hyderabad, India

Role: Software Developer, Project: QREX Tool for actuarials.

QREX is stands for Quotes Rates Extracts and CrossReference, This is an internal tool which all the actuarials(Humana Business Uses) will use to test rates and the request response of the quotes and rate service. Also used to extract the applications to send downstream systems like Mainframes. This tool provides environment to run the different jobs which we did developed like AM Extract, HPS Extract and UWDB Extracts.

- Developed the services using WCF to access catalog and basket related functionalities.
- Developed web pages using ASP.NET, JavaScript and Client Side Validation.
- Implemented Entity Framework and LINQ for querying, sorting, filtering the complex objects.
- Configured Security features for the application using Form Based Authentication and Role Based Authentication using C# and ASP.Net.
- Implemented Razor Views and Partial Views
- Created Stored Procedures, Functions, Views and Triggers in MS-SQL database using T-SQL for regulate and maintain complex data.

2012 July - 2015 October

Syntel Pvt. Ltd, Customer Humana, USA

Work Location: Chennai, India.

Role: Software Developer, Project: Hospital Management System.

Call Center Application (CC): Consumers can call to call center executive and get the quotation. Online Consumer Application (OC): This application is useful to complete a basic quote which is created using above applications AWB or D2C. AgentWorkBench Application (AWB): Consumers can go to Agents OR Agents can go to consumers and create a basic. PIP post issues Policies: Provide users to change the policies with this PIP tool for Humana. Creation of different types of services using Web API

- Played a role of programmer involved in Analysis, Screen Design, Development, **Deployment and Testing**
- Design and code moderately complex components that meet functional and business requirements on schedule.
- Fixing the problem reports (bugs) and updating in Version control system.
- Involved in writing Server Side validations and Unit Test cases.
- Participated in design and code reviews.
- Involved in development execution planning.



LANGUAGES

English

Advanced Professional

Telugu

Native

Hindi

Native